Hello.
In this lesson, we are going to see how to convert the how to configure the ADC using our Cuba mix
when it creates a new project.
Come over here.
You project.
And then also liked my port.
So we are going to see different methods for initialize and the ADC.
We first going to see this single mode conversion and then we're going to see the continuous mode conversion.
After that, we going to see how to crigger the ADC conversion using a timer.
And then we're going to see how to sort of configure multiple ADC channels and using the DMA to do that.
So come over here or select SDM 32 for one one.
Then I double click this.
Gopin.
So we start off by clearing the penult.
Claire Penult over were here.
Then I'm going to set up the, um, the core.
Over here, we're using the sewer wire.
And then RCC over here going to bypass this.
Then this we're gonna use the crystal.
So our estimate there are two for one, one has just one ADC module.
So we can come over here to analog.
And there's just ADC one.
However, this single ADC module gives us 16 channels.
Right.
So I'm going to select in zero here for input's channel zero.
Okay.
And this experiment, we can leave everything here on the parameters set in is the same.
We don't need to change anything.
Right.
So we can generate our code now.
So we just come to project manager over here.
I'm going to select my two chain is SDM 32.
Cube E.
I'll call this project ADC underscore single mode conversion.
Once that is done, click over here to generate we can open our project.
So this whole project I double click here to open.
Open the main door to see fall and then clean up a bit.
So now the first thing we have to do is start the ADC to do that.
We go to the ADC module to see the function out.
Allow us to do that.
So come over here and find the ADC.
Don't see fall.
So I hear.
See?
So we have the function for initialise in these initialise, and as well, the one we're looking for
is the start function we can search by doing control F and then we can simply search ADC underscore
start.
And this is it.
So there are two versions there starts with interrupt and there is just start.
We miss this thought.
This is ATC stops with the one above should be ATC start.
This is it.
OK.
So this just takes a pointer to the ADC Hondo, so I couldn't copy this and take it to our main see.
So after we initialize the ADC, then we start the ADC.
So this takes the ADC Hando, which is up here.
Clean this.
This or ADC one, Hunda.
So take this with Pasos, like you went to this function and post the address over here like this.
Over here like this.
Right.
So this will start the easy one.
Now, the next thing we need to do is pull for conversion.
So we need to get a function down, allow us to pull for conversion when the conversion is complete.
When I store the resort in a variable.
So let's do it.
So let's go to what ADC module.
So let's search for plan for conversion.
Control F and the P or L.
L for conversion o.
Like this.
Okay.
So there is this function hall ADC poll for conversion.
It takes the ADC Hondo and a time out.
We can copy this if you want to read more about the function.
You can read the brief here.
Pool for regular conversion complete.
Right.
So this parameter time out value is in milliseconds.
So is the timeout amount.
I should say.
Copy this.
And then bring it over here.
So we place our pool for conversion here.
The first argument is the ADC handle, so HTC One, HTC One over here and a time out, we can give it
time out of one Emmas.
That is fine.
So now that we've bought for conversion, we have to use a third function, which is to get the conversion
or stop put in comment here.
Number one, you start the ADC.
Number two.
Pull for conversion.
Then number three.
We get to conversion.
Okay.
So these are the three steps.
So let's grab the third function.
I'll come over here.
It's known as they get value function.
So control f
okay over here gets value and we can read about it says.
Gets the converted value from the data.
Right.
You start off regular Cherno.
This one just takes the ADC handle.
So argument and then it returns the value returned to you in 32, which is the ADC value.
So put that in here.
And then I'm going to pass our ADC one Hondo here.
This plus one this.
The address like this.
And then some cool on over here.
So this function is going to return the ADC value that you would read from Channel from the ADC one.
And we've configured only Channel Zero.
So I'm going to create a global variable to hold the resort.
You end thirty two 30 to underscore t, I call this sense of value.
Then over here, sense of value is going to have the return of the get value function like this.
And these steps we can keep them in the infinite loop.
Cut them from here.
Push them over here like this.
Okay, so now we can test all board.
We need to connect a sensor to ADC Channel Zero and then we can read the volume from the watch window.
We can read a sense of value from Watch Windu.
We can use a potential meter as our senseor in this experiment.
So by 10 and the knob of the potential meter, you basically change in the analog reading.
Remember, the potential meter has three legs.
The middle leg is the one that goes to our ADC pin, which is P is zero for ADC Channel zero.
And then the left leg can go to ground and then the rightmost leg can go to the VCT, which is the voltage
source.
So you can connect your potential meter Mido leg to the ADC, pin the left one to ground and then the
right like to eat up five votaw, three point three vote depending on the board you are using.
And if you're using the nuclear connected to the FIVE-FOLD.
Yeah.
So we can build our project.
A click over here to build.
To appeared in.
Well, we have an error somewhere.
What does it say so value on declared?
Oh, I've got a typo here.
OK.
Click here to build.
Okay, to build successfully.
And then we can click here to go to the D-Box you.
OK.
These expressions are from a previous project.
We can delete them.
So now we're going to add a sense of value to the expression controversy to copy and then control fee
to paste over here, and then I'm going to click here to run the code.
It says Target not available.
Okay, so I'm going to take a look at my debugger, right?
So, um, let's go to the debugger again.
Click over here.
It's open in.
Right.
So we if we run this, that's gonna tell us that target's not available is because we're using the,
uh, we use the wrong window.
This one is called expressions.
But to monitor a, well, global variables, we have to use the live expressions, video, uh, window
so we can come over.
Okay.
Escape the debug view.
Sorry about that.
Now go again.
I'll click over here on this bug over here.
So I'm going to close this window.
This window called Expression's, I'll close it and I'm going to come over here to window and then sure
window and then I'll select live expressions.
You should be here somewhere.
This live expression is the issue.
Yes, they have the same icon.
That is why it's a bit confusing.
So if you want to want to tell your global variables, you use the live expressions.
So over here, my global variable is added.
But let's see if you started.
You had no global variable.
I'm trying to clean it.
To other global.
For a while.
You can just copy the name of the variable and click on expressions over here and then paste the name.
So I have this other twice.
No problem.
So, um, yeah.
So to run our code.
Click over here to run.
And this is this is the ADC value, and this is based on the current position of my potential, Meeta.
And I'm going to move the potential meta.
I say move it.
You see that the value goes down.
I've moved it to the right.
Most position.
I've moved it to the to the direction towards the, um, the direction of the pin that connects to ground.
That is why we record in a very low value.
I'm going to move it to the opposite direction, the very end of the opposite direction.
And as I move, you see the, um, the ADC value increases.
So this is how to configure the ADC.
And then we shall go on and see two other examples, at least two other examples which regards to ADC
configuration.
If you have any questions at all, live in the community section and I'll see you later.
Have a nice day.